Lumbard, Eliot H.; Papers apap071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Private Practice, 1951-1999
  - Cases, 1951-1999
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Memorandum of the Office Parent Creditors Committee in Opposition to Motion for Partial Summary Judgement, 1989 April (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cyprus Minerals Case- Memorandums in Support of Claimants and Counter Defendants Motion for Partial Summary Judgement, 1989 January (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Post Settlement, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Post Settlement Newsclippings Cyprus and LTV Reports, 1993-1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Cases- Possible LTV Plans, 1988 August (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Proof of Claim (1 of 2), 1987 November (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Proof of Claim (2 of 2), 1987 November (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Transcript of Argument on the Summary Judgement Motion, 1989 May (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cyprus Minerals Company Case- Various Motions and Memorandum, 1989 January (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Equity Funding Case - Boston Company Institutional Investors, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Equity Funding Life Insurance, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Equity Funding Life Insurance Company of New York- Equity Funding Corporation of America, Bankruptcy Investigation, Litigation, Trustee Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Goebel Brewings v. Anaconda Wire and Cable, North American Aviation v. Renegotiation Board, U.S. v. Union Carbide, et.al. (Vanadum Corp. of America), Assigned Criminal Cases, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Grolier Incorporated and the Richards Company Inc. - Re: The Crowell - Collier Publishing and P.F. Collier and Son Corporation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - In The Matter of Reynolds and Co., Reynolds Securities Inc., HallGarten and Co., William D. Witter Inc., and The Detroit Bank and Trust Co. "Certain Trading in The Common Stock of Faberge, Inc.", 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - In the Matter of Roy M. Cohn - Departmental Disciplinary Committee Proceedings, 1975-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - In the Matter of Roy M. Cohn - First Court Proceedings, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - In the Matter of Roy M. Cohn - Second Court Proceedings, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ira Haupt and Co. Case - Affidavit Fidelity, Bunge Corporation, and Chase Manhattan Bank, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Ira Haupt and Co. Case - Correspondence with Anthony DeAngelis, Christmas Cards, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ira Haupt and Co. Case- Transcript of Witness Anthony DeAngelis, 1965 November (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - James Arnel and Vernon A. Stockwell v. Reynolds and Co. and Ralph E. Carpenter - (United States District Court for the Southern District of New York), Trial Memoranda and Notes, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - James Arnel and Vernon A. Stockwell v. Reynolds and Co. and Ralph E. Carpenter - United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, Trial Transcript Vol. 2, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Manwillie Trust- Asbestos Case, 1990-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - National Awareness Foundations v. State of New York - Last Opinion, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Palisades Life Insurance Company (1 of 2), 1964-1969 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Palisades Life Insurance Company (2 of 2), 1964-1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Palisades Life Insurance Company and Equity Funding Life Insurance Company of New York - Annual Statements, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Palisades Life Insurance Company - Corporate Documents, 1971- 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Palisades Life Insurance Company - Sale to American General Life Insurance Company of Delaware, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Port of Portland v. Cape Edmont, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Reynolds Securities Inc. - Selected Materials From Anti-Trust Litigation RE: Commission Rates For Commodities Trading on the Chicago Board of Trade Vol. I, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Reynolds Securities Inc. - Selected Materials From Anti-Trust Litigation RE: Commission Rates For Commodities Trading on the Chicago Board of Trade Vol. II, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Reynolds Securities Inc. - Selected Materials From Anti-Trust Litigation RE: Commission Rates For Commodities Trading on the Chicago Board of Trade Vol. III, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reynolds Security Case, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Roy Cohn (1 of 2), 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Roy Cohn (2 of 2), 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Roy M. Cohn, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Sentencing Provisions of the New Crime Control, 1984 October (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - United States Bankruptcy Court For The Southern District of New York In Re. Meritum Corporation - Papers and Reports of the Trustee; Eliot H. Lumbard Vol. V, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - United States District Court for the Southern District of New York- In The Matter of Universal Money Order Co., Debtor (A Chapter XI Proceeding), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Universal Money Order Company Case Investigation Report, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Universal Money Order Company Case Legal Notes and Newsclippings, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Universal Money Order Company Case -Newsclipping (1 of 2), 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Universal Money Order Company Case- Newsclipping (2 of 2), 1977-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Westinghouse/Uranium Case, 1977- 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Firms, 1963-1990
    This subseries contains directories, manuals, financials, correspondence, and reports from various law firms that Lumbard worked at.
    - Business Lunches and Dinners, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Directories and Announcements, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Eliot H. Lumbard P.C.- Firm Financial Statements, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Eliot Lumbard P.C.- Fiscal Record, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Eliot H. Lumbard P.C., Lumbard and Phelan P.C.- Fiscal Year (1 of 2), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Eliot H. Lumbard P.C., Lumbard and Phelan P.C. - Fiscal Year (2 of 2), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Expense Account, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Haight, Gardner, Poor and Havens- Annual Reviews, 1988; 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Haight, Gardner, Poor, Havens- "United States Admiralty Cargo Law" - China Ocean Shipping Company, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Haight, Gardner - "Transnational Reorganization Coping with the Insolvent Multinational" by EHL on the Japan Shipping Exchange, Tokyo, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters of Congratulations- Regarding Joining Haight, Gardner, Poor and Havens, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters of Congratulations Regarding Opening of Lumbard and Phelan, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters of Congratulations Regarding Partnership with Saul, Ewing, Remick and Saul (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters of Congratulations Regarding Partnership with Saul, Ewing, Remick and Saul (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Certificate of Incorporation, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lumbard and Phelan- Client File Numbers (1 of 2), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Client File Numbers (2 of 2), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Lumbard and Phelan- Directories - RESTRICTED, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Must consult an archivist before viewing this material.
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Financial Statements, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Financials, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lumbard and Phelan Financials, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Firm Manual, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Fiscal Year, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Fiscal Year, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Fiscal Year, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Lumbard and Phelan, Open Professional Engagement - Office Administration Matters (1 of 2), 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Lumbard and Phelan, Open Professional Engagement - Office Administration Matters (2 of 2), 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lumbard and Phelan - Partnership Agreement, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photo -Lumbard and Office Staff, 1980 February (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Saul, Ewing, Remick and Saul, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Saul, Ewing, Remick and Saul- Final Accounting, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Spear and Hill Correspondence - Harvey Spear, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Spear and Hill - Directories, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Spear and Hill Dissolution Agreement, 1975 December (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Spear and Hill Financials, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Spear and Hill Financials, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Spear and Hill Financials, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Tax Returns - RESTRICTED, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Townsend and Lewis - Financials, 1963-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Trip Report- Seoul, South Korea, Hong Kong, and Tokyo Japan, 1986 September-October (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Teaching, 1964-1999; 8; 2.22 cubic ft.
  This series concerns Lumbard’s work as an adjunct professor and lecturer at John Jay College, Rutgers University, and SUNY Albany. It contains course readings, lecture notes, course booklets, bulletins, academic papers, and correspondence.
  - Illinois State University Dept. of Criminal Justice Prof. Frank Morn, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Introduction to Bankruptcy: History and Context" List by Eliot Lumbard, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, 1975-1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, 1977-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, 1980-1981; 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Book Lists, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Course Readings, 1977-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Crime Control Policy Making, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Crime Control Policy Making, 1976 Fall (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Crime Control Policy Making - Course Readings, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice - Crime Control Policy Making - Lecture Notes, 1975 Fall (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Crime Control Policy Making - Professor's Notes, 1979 Spring (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice- Schedule and Readings, 1978 September (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Model Probation Reports for Second Circuit Sentencing Institute, 1973 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey- Center of Criminal Justice, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rutgers University- School of Criminal Justice, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rutgers University- School of Criminal Justice, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rutgers University- School of Criminal Justice, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1968-1975 (Oversized 22)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, The Beginnings, 1964-1975 (Oversized 22)
  - SUNY Albany - Academic Papers on Establishment of the School of Criminal Justice, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - SUNY Albany- "Community Alternatives to Maximum Security Institutionalization"- Report to Institute for Public Policy Alternatives, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SUNY Albany- International Criminal Justice Unit Idea, 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SUNY Albany- Lumbard Donation, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SUNY Albany- Report of Private Giving, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - SUNY Albany- Rockefeller Institute Bulletin, Foundation Annual Report, Commencement, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1972; 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice, 1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice Academic Paper and Journal Articles- By Jerome Skalnick and David Bayley, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice Alumni Association, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice Banquet- 20th Anniversary of the First Graduating Class, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice Brochures, Newsletters, Correspondence, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Deans Report, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Distinguished Service Award, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Establishment, Handbook, Correspondence, 1976; 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- "Existing Correctional Placements and Internships in New York State" by Charles Prigmore, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Founding, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Graduate School, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Introduction of the School of Criminal Justice, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Report on the Establishment of a School of Criminology and Criminal Justice and Criminal Justice by the State University of New York, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- "Shots Fired: An Examination of NYC Police Firearms Discharge" by James Joseph Fyfe (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- "Shots Fired: An Examination of NYC Police Firearms Discharge" by James Joseph Fyfe (2 of 2), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Symposium on the Creation of the School of Criminal Justice, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SUNY Albany- School of Criminal Justice- Visiting Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1960-1996; 9; 1.72 cubic ft.
  This series contains Lumbard’s general, office and personal correspondence.
  - "Antidote for the Non-System? Criminal Justice Superagenies" - Correspondence with Daniel Skoler, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - General Correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1977-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence including EHL's Letter of Resignation fromm Position of Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence- Leslie Wilkins, Cambridge, England, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence- Movie or Series Deal, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence- New York State Division of Criminal Justice Services, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence- News Clippings, Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1972-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence (1 of 2), 1960 January-1961 February (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Personal Correspondence (2 of 2), 1960 January-1961 February (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence (2 of 2), 1975 May- 1976 December (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence (2 of 2), 1977 January- 1978 December (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence Letters from Viola Contiguglia, 1989 August - 1990 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - South Street Seaport Correspondence, 1969; 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - South Street Seaport Correspondence, Undated (Flat-file 1)
  - Townsend and Lewis - Bound Book of Memorandum, 1962-1963 (Oversized 23)
- Personal Files, 1943-2001; 10; .50 cubic ft.
  This series contains Lumbard’s personal files. It consists of his military papers, professional certificates and awards, curriculum vitae, FBI File, and directories, as well as other personal items.
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York Membership Certificates, 1953-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Attorney Registration Forms New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Big Brother Inc. - New York City, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business Cards, Greeting Cards, Gag Photos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cards Written to Lumbard, 1977; 1988; 1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Colombia University- Organizations, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eliot Lumbard and Susan Lynn Lumbard- Poems, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Esalen Catalog, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Esalen Catalog, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Esalen Catalog, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Esalen- Newsclippings, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Haight, Gardner, Poor and Havens- Joining the Firm Plaque, 1986 January 15 (Oversized 24)
  - Lumbard and Phelan - Formation of Partnership Plaque, 1977 January 1 (Oversized 24)
  - Lumbard's FBI File, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Merchant Marine and U.S. Marinetime Service, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - MIS Certificates Memberships to Various Organizations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Organization Masters, Mates and Pilots of America, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notary Public, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NYS Bar Registration, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NY State Court of Appeals- Compliance Certificate, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Personal Items, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Reflections: By Herbert Isaacs- 13/100-Signed by Author with Note to Eliot Lumbard, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Schuyler Otis Bland Memorial Library Kings Point, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Summary of Litigation Experience, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Travel Brochures; Letter from EHL Children, Newsclippings, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Upper West Side Development- Newsclipping, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Navel Reserves Officer Service Records, 1945-1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Western District of New York License to Practice, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1960-1999; 11; 3.33 cubic ft.
  This series contains criminal justice material that Lumbard devoted his life toward studying. The series includes journal articles, booklets, pamphlets, press releases, memos, news clippings, academic papers, and reports.
  - Atlantic Magazine- "The Police and the Rest of Us", 1969 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Crime and Criminal Justice- Newsclippings, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Crime and Criminal Justice- Newsclippings and Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Crime and Politics Newsclippings (1 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Crime and Politics Newsclippings (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Newsletter- Newsclippings, Press Releases, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Estimated Percentages of Bookmaking in Central N.Y. State, Undated (Flat-file 2)
  - Gambling Newsclippings, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Governor Rockefeller's New Narcotics Law Will Protect You Against Addicts. And Addicts Against Themselves, Undated (Flat-file 3)
  - Harpers Magazine- Crime and Punishment Supplement, 1964 April (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Journal Articles, Press Releases Report, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Law Enforcement and Information Sharing- Academic Papers, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nelson Rockefeller - Passionate Millioniare, 1996 (Video-tape 1)
  - News Articles, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Newsclippings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Newsclippings, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Newsclippings -Notes, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Newsclippings and Notes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings and Notes, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newsclippings, Newsletters "New Frontiers in Criminal Justice Research", 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nesclippings and Press Releases, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings and Press Releases, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings, Obits, and Magazine Articles, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, Obits, and Magazine Articles, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newclippings and Press Releases (1 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings and Press Releases (2 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, Press Releases, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings, Press Releases, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newsclippngs, Press Releases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings, Press Releases, Newsletters, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings, Press Releases, Newsletters, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings, Reports, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings Collected by President's Commission on Violence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings Collected by President's Commission on Violence, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Newsclippings and Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, Newsclippings- Crime Control Digest - The Criminal Law Reporter, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Press Releases, Newsclippings, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, Academic Papers, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, Newsletters, Newsclipping, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, Reports, Memos, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, Reports, Academic Papers, Newsclippings (1 of 2), 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, Reports, Academic Papers, Newsclippings (2 of 2), 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Racial Violence Newsclippings (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Racial Violence Newsclippings (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Newsclippings, and Journal Articles, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Research NYS Criminal Justice Newclippings, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Research Report on U.S. Social Programs, Various Articles, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Research- Violence in the Media, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Violence Newsclippings, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Vote for New York - Re-Elect John Lindsay, Undated (Flat-file 4)
- Audio, 1963 -1971; 12; .26 cubic ft.
  This series contains 7” audio reels concerning criminal justice.
  - Alan Watts: Against Age Religious Services - Experimental Session, 1971 April 18
  - Alan Watts: Against Age Religious Services, 1971
  - Crime and the Continental Cop, #18, Undated
  - Crime and What, #21, Undated
  - Crime in the Affluent World #16, Last Six Tapes (#16-21) Crime and Punishment in the 60s, Undated
  - The English Prison, #20, Undated
  - Exec. Comm., Undated
  - The Gangs of London, #19, Undated
  - Searchlight, 1963 September
  - The Young in the Affluent World, #17, Undated